<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CogSci C100 on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/cogsci-c100/</link><description>Recent content in CogSci C100 on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/cogsci-c100/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/intro/</guid><description>Overview and Fields # Cognitive Science: Study of the mind and cognition that integrates a number of different academic disciplines: Neuroscientists study the mind’s biological machinery Psychologists directly study mental processes, such as perception, learning/memory, judgement and decision-making Computer scientists explore how those processes can be simulated and modeled in computers Philosophers ask critical questions about the nature of the mind &amp;ndash; what is mind? how does it interface with body?</description></item><item><title>Perception</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/perception/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/perception/</guid><description>Definition of sensation and perception # As humans, we are cognitive beings who&amp;hellip; Acquire information about the world around us Integrate that information with prior knowledge from our stored memory Store that knowledge in our memory so we can use it later to help us achieve our goals First step in this process of acquiring knowledge about the world involves sensation and perception Sensation: process by which our sensory receptors and nervous system receive stimulus energies from the environment and transduce them into neural impulses.</description></item></channel></rss>