<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CogSci C100 on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/cogsci-c100/</link><description>Recent content in CogSci C100 on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/cogsci-c100/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/intro/</guid><description>Overview and Fields # Cognitive Science: Study of the mind and cognition that integrates a number of different academic disciplines: Neuroscientists study the mind’s biological machinery Psychologists directly study mental processes, such as perception, learning/memory, judgement and decision-making Computer scientists explore how those processes can be simulated and modeled in computers Philosophers ask critical questions about the nature of the mind &amp;ndash; what is mind? how does it interface with body?</description></item><item><title>Perception</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/perception/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/perception/</guid><description>Definition of sensation and perception # As humans, we are cognitive beings who&amp;hellip; Acquire information about the world around us (perception) Integrate that information with prior knowledge from our stored memory Store that knowledge in our memory so we can use it later to help us achieve our goals First step in this process of acquiring knowledge about the world involves sensation and perception Sensation: process by which our sensory receptors and nervous system receive stimulus energies from the environment and transduce them into neural impulses (transduction).</description></item><item><title>Non-Visual Perception</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/non-visual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/non-visual/</guid><description>Auditory Perception: Psychological Effects Of Music # Effects Of Music On Cognition # Music has been found to influence memory, decision making, and other cognitive processes Study conducted in supermarkets found that use of slow background music increased sales by 38% over use of fast music - shoppers stayed in store longer and bought more, a lot more (Milliman, R.E., 1986) Particularly effective for purchasing decisions with high affective/low cognitive involvement, e.</description></item><item><title>Attention</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/attention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/attention/</guid><description>Physiological/neurological measures of attention # Attention: ability to focus on one thing and ignore others Attention is required for information to be encoded Novel stimuli capture attention &amp;ndash; something that&amp;rsquo;s different Can be something loud, bright, salient or even sudden sound of silence Physiological/neurological measures of attention Neurological correlates (ERP and PET studies) Activation of anterior and posterior attentional networks (frontal lobe) Orienting response Increase in heart rate and galvanic skin response Pupil dilation Pupil dilation reflects attentional effort &amp;ndash; pupils expand when people deep in thought If you are shown picture of someone you are romantically attracted to, your pupils dilate We are also more attracted to pictures of people with expanded pupils In marketing/advertising, pupils are enlarged in models In 19C, ladies used to put belladonna in their eyes Eye movement changes Eyes tend to move toward objects of attention (even auditory attention) A number of newly developed therapies focus specifically on maintaining eye contact as a way of enhancing attunement and detecting when a person is dissociating (e.</description></item><item><title>Sleep &amp; Dreams</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/sleep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/sleep/</guid><description>Sleep and cognition # The National Sleep Foundation’s Sleep IQ Test During sleep, your brain rests. Boredom makes you feel sleepy, even if you have had enough sleep. Resting in bed with your eyes closed cannot satisfy your body’s need for sleep. Snoring is not harmful as long as it doesn’t disturb others. Everyone dreams nightly. Raising the volume of your radio will help you stay awake while driving.</description></item><item><title>Consciousness</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/consciousness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/consciousness/</guid><description>The mind-brain problem: What is mind? # The nature of the mind-body or mind-brain connection was a philosophical question of importance in the early days of cognitive science What is mind? Is it something that is physical? Is a body necessary to have a mind? We don&amp;rsquo;t talk too much about philosophy since it&amp;rsquo;s inherently not empirical / verifiable It&amp;rsquo;s all that was possible 50 years ago Now we have neuroscience!</description></item></channel></rss>