<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>0: Intro &amp; Tolerancing</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/0/</guid><description>01-18: Course introduction # Overview # This class focuses on three main components &amp;ndash; manufacturing processes, dimensional tolerances, and design communication &amp;ndash; and how they interact with one another.
The class is made up of 9 modules:
Fundamentals Subtractive manufacturing processes Additive manufacturing processes Forming processes Joining processes Graphical visualization techniques Metrology: measuring manufactured objects Geometric dimensioning and tolerancing The future of manufacturing Why manufacturing? # In 2018, U.</description></item><item><title>0: System Design &amp; Linear Equations</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/0/</guid><description>01-18: Course Introduction # Slides Notes 0, 1A All logistics, no notes!
01-20: Introduction to Imaging, Tomography, and Linear Equations # Slides Notes 1A, 1B System Design # We use devices, such as imagers, that provide information, such as a visual representation of a system Often, these devices don’t work alone &amp;ndash; they are part of a larger system that uses a combination of both physical sensors and signal processing techniques.</description></item><item><title>1: Introduction</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/intro/</guid><description>Overview and Fields # Cognitive Science: Study of the mind and cognition that integrates a number of different academic disciplines: Neuroscientists study the mind’s biological machinery Psychologists directly study mental processes, such as perception, learning/memory, judgement and decision-making Computer scientists explore how those processes can be simulated and modeled in computers Philosophers ask critical questions about the nature of the mind &amp;ndash; what is mind? how does it interface with body?</description></item><item><title>1: Fundamentals of Graphical Communication &amp; Subtractive Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/1/</guid><description>01-25: Fundamentals of graphical communication # Evolution of graphical visualization # Hand drawing Instrument drawing (using mechanical things to measure distances) 2D CAD (initially only able to draw side views) 3D CAD (solid modeling) Automatic generation of 2D working drawings Enable easy communication of measurements between designer and manufacturer Created with the assumption that manufactured objects are made up of elementary objects, geons? Now we have the ability to run algos to analyze models, removing unnecessary bits We&amp;rsquo;re moving towards computer-generated geometry that&amp;rsquo;s contained by human input # Increasingly complex geometries Topological optimization Internal lattices The way we interface with drawings has to keep up with this New interfaces Virtual and augmented reality for visualizing designs Why bother sketching by hand?</description></item><item><title>1: Gaussian Elim. &amp; Matrices + Vectors</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/1/</guid><description>01-25: Gaussian Elimination, Vectors # Slides Notes 2A, 2B Upper Triangular Systems # Consider the following equation $$x-y+2z=1$$ $$y-z=2$$ $$z=1$$ &amp;hellip;which can be represent as an augmented matrix: $$\begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp;amp; -1 &amp;amp; 2 &amp;amp; \text{|} &amp;amp; 1\\ 0 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; -1 &amp;amp; \text{|} &amp;amp; 2\\ 0 &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; \text{|} &amp;amp; 1 \end{bmatrix}$$ These are called upper triangle matrices &amp;ndash; they are nice in that they&amp;rsquo;re easy to solve!</description></item><item><title>2: Perception</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/perception/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/perception/</guid><description>Definition of sensation and perception # As humans, we are cognitive beings who&amp;hellip; Acquire information about the world around us (perception) Integrate that information with prior knowledge from our stored memory Store that knowledge in our memory so we can use it later to help us achieve our goals First step in this process of acquiring knowledge about the world involves sensation and perception Sensation: process by which our sensory receptors and nervous system receive stimulus energies from the environment and transduce them into neural impulses (transduction).</description></item><item><title>2: (In)dependence &amp; Circuit Analysis</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/2/</guid><description>02-01: Linear (in)dependance, Matrix Transformations # Slides Note 3 Recall the simple tomography example from Note 1, in which we tried to determine the composition of a box of bottles by shining light at different angles and measuring light absorption. The Gaussian elimination algorithm implied that we needed to take at least 9 measurements to properly identify the 9 bottles in a box so that we had at least one equation per variable.</description></item><item><title>2: Cutting-based Processes &amp; Other Subtractive Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/2/</guid><description>02-01 Cutting-based Processes # Modeling of material cutting # Chips are created and separated from the work by plastic deformation, i.e. shearing, of the work. Sheer plane is created by the tool (teal segment) Throughout the shear plane, the shear stress must equal or exceed the shear strength of the work material for cutting to proceed. The value of the shear angle is not something that we directly control, but depends on several factors.</description></item><item><title>3: Non-Visual Perception</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/non-visual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/non-visual/</guid><description>Auditory Perception: Psychological Effects Of Music # Effects Of Music On Cognition # Music has been found to influence memory, decision making, and other cognitive processes Study conducted in supermarkets found that use of slow background music increased sales by 38% over use of fast music - shoppers stayed in store longer and bought more, a lot more (Milliman, R.E., 1986) Particularly effective for purchasing decisions with high affective/low cognitive involvement, e.</description></item><item><title>3: Additive Processes: Intro &amp; Extrusion</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/3/</guid><description>The rise of additive manufacturing # Additive manufacturing or “3D printing” has been receiving enormous attention both in industry and as a tool for education and design. Something that sets additive manufacturing apart from other families of processes is the enormous rate of innovation in process technology and machine design, together with the fact that much of this innovation is done by small start-up companies and even by individuals, with the development in some cases being crowd-funded.</description></item><item><title>3: Transformations &amp; Inverse</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/3/</guid><description>02-08: Matrix Transformations # Slides Note 4 Linear Transformations # Linear Transformation: In the previous practice set, we discussed the idea of a matrix .$A^{M \times N}$ as a linear transformation. Effectively, in the equation .$A \vec x = \vec b$, the matrix itself can be considered a transformation .$f : \mathbb{R}^{N} \to \mathbb{R}^{M}$ which takes a vector .$\vec x^{N \times 1}$ of inputs and returns a vector .</description></item><item><title>4: Attention</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/attention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/attention/</guid><description>Physiological/neurological measures of attention # Attention: ability to focus on one thing and ignore others Attention is required for information to be encoded Novel stimuli capture attention &amp;ndash; something that&amp;rsquo;s different Can be something loud, bright, salient or even sudden sound of silence Physiological/neurological measures of attention Neurological correlates (ERP and PET studies) Activation of anterior and posterior attentional networks (frontal lobe) Orienting response Increase in heart rate and galvanic skin response Pupil dilation Pupil dilation reflects attentional effort &amp;ndash; pupils expand when people deep in thought If you are shown picture of someone you are romantically attracted to, your pupils dilate We are also more attracted to pictures of people with expanded pupils In marketing/advertising, pupils are enlarged in models In 19C, ladies used to put belladonna in their eyes Eye movement changes Eyes tend to move toward objects of attention (even auditory attention) A number of newly developed therapies focus specifically on maintaining eye contact as a way of enhancing attunement and detecting when a person is dissociating (e.</description></item><item><title>4: Additive Processes: Light-based, etc.</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/4/</guid><description>Processes based on light-sensitive liquids # Stereolithography (SLA) # Also called Digital Light Printing (DLP) Thermoforming molds are most commonly made with stereolithography, i.e orthodontic aligners Used because the molds need complete geometric customizability A tray, bath or vat of a photo-sensitive liquid (a resin) is locally crosslinked (solidified) with a scanning laser beam or projected light pattern (i.e Photoinitiator), usually violet (~405 nm) or ultraviolet (~365 nm) Unwanted bonding can be avoided by making the base oxygen-permeable (e.</description></item><item><title>4: Vector Spaces &amp; Eigenstuff</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/4/</guid><description>02-15: Vector Spaces: Null Spaces and Columnspaces # Slides Notes 7 8 Important Jargon # Rank a matrix .$A$ is the number of linearly independent columns Nullspace of a matrix is the set of solutions to .$A \vec x = 0$ A vector space is a set of vectors connected by two operators: .$+, \times$ &amp;mdash; page 48 A vector subspace is a subset of vectors that have “nice properties” &amp;mdash; page 50 A basis for a vector space is a minimum set of vectors needed to represent all vectors in the space Dimension of a vector space is the number of basis vectors Column space is the span (range) of the columns of a matrix Row space is the span of the rows of a matrix Vector Spaces # A vector space .</description></item><item><title>5: Sleep &amp; Dreams</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/sleep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/sleep/</guid><description>Sleep and cognition # The National Sleep Foundation’s Sleep IQ Test During sleep, your brain rests. Boredom makes you feel sleepy, even if you have had enough sleep. Resting in bed with your eyes closed cannot satisfy your body’s need for sleep. Snoring is not harmful as long as it doesn’t disturb others. Everyone dreams nightly. Raising the volume of your radio will help you stay awake while driving.</description></item><item><title>5-6: Forming Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/5/</guid><description>Before # So far in the class, we have seen a wide range of additive and subtractive processes which are capable of creating components in metals, alloys, polymeric materials, ceramics, and composites. The one thing that these processes all have in common is that they are serial — meaning that one feature is produced after another in a predefined sequence. This serial nature inherently limits productivity and may require considerable operator skill.</description></item><item><title>5: Basis &amp; Circuit Analysis</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/5/</guid><description>02-22 Basis # Note 10 Slides Change of Basis # Previously we’ve seen that a basis for a vector space is a minimal spanning set of vectors. We can also define the standard basis vectors, e,x. the standard basis for .$ \mathbb{R}^{3}$ is the set .$\mathbb{E}$: $$\mathbb{E} = \big(\hat i, \hat j, \hat k \big)$$ $$\dots \equiv ( \vec e_1, \vec e_2, \vec e_3)$$ $$\dots \equiv \left( \begin{bmatrix} 1\\ 0\\ 0\\ \end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix} 0\\ 1\\ 0\\ \end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix} 0\\ 0\\ 1\\ \end{bmatrix}\right) $$ We can represent any set of vectors that form as basis as a linear combination of the standard .</description></item><item><title>6: Consciousness</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/consciousness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/consciousness/</guid><description>The mind-brain problem: What is mind? # The nature of the mind-body or mind-brain connection was a philosophical question of importance in the early days of cognitive science What is mind? Is it something that is physical? Is a body necessary to have a mind? We don&amp;rsquo;t talk too much about philosophy since it&amp;rsquo;s inherently not empirical / verifiable It&amp;rsquo;s all that was possible 50 years ago Now we have neuroscience!</description></item><item><title>6: Voltage Dividers &amp; Measurement</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/6/</guid><description>03-01: Voltage Dividers # Voltage Divider # The voltage divider circuit consists of a voltage source (.$V_S$) and two resistors (.$R_1$ and .$R_2$) Example: We label the node connected to the voltage supply as .$u_1 (= V_S)$, since the voltage supply goes between this node and ground. Label the remaining node as .$u_\text{mid}$ and the voltages and currents through every element in the circuit with .$V_i$ and .</description></item><item><title>6-7: Joining processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/6/</guid><description>\(\) Joining Processes # Welding-based # There are many ways of assembling mechanical components to create mechanisms and structures. Examples of joining processes include the use of fasteners such as bolts and rivets, adhesives, and push fits, in which interference is used to connect components together. Welding, meanwhile, involves fusing two components by melting the material near their interface, and possibly introducing additional material of the same kind to fill any gaps between the components.</description></item><item><title>7: 2D Touchscreens &amp; Superp. + Equivalence</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/7/</guid><description>03-08: 2D Resistive Touchscreens # Bottom Plate # Trivially, we see that if we add a wire connected to .$u_\text{mid}$ that will have the same voltage across it (wires have zero voltage drop) So why have the bottom plate at all? It lets us take the measurement for .$V_\text{out}$ using connection points on the edge of the plate instead of having to put a probe or wire at the actual touch point every time!</description></item><item><title>7: Mindfulness</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mindfulness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mindfulness/</guid><description>Mindfulness, awareness and acceptance # Why Study Mindfulness? # Western research has indicated that meditation can be effectively used to: Treat psychological disorders, including anxiety, depression, substance abuse, eating disorders, sleep disorders, ADHD, and conduct disorder Recent reviews indicate that overall effect sizes are modest, but mindfulness is still considered an evidence-based treatment for most psychological disorders The small effects are comparable with what would be expected from the use of psychotropic medications (e.</description></item><item><title>7-9: Visualization</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/7/</guid><description>Orthographic projections # Formal (working) drawings: purpose # Need a formal way of documenting designs Legal documents i.e patents; contracts may rely on them Must stand on their own &amp;ndash; readable to any human No subsequent explanation No verbal assists No ambiguity Solution: multi-view orthographic projection World-wide engineering standard Can easily include tolerances What is a projection?</description></item><item><title>8: Capacitors &amp; Capacitive Touchscreen</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/8/</guid><description>\(\) 03/15 Capacitors # Structure and Physics # See also, 7B 24 Capacitors is a circuit element that stores charge Positive charges build up on the (top) surface of the plate connected to the positive terminal and negative charges build up on the (bottom) surface of the plate connected to the negative terminal. Capacitors have an associated quantity, $C$apacitance; the ratio of the amount of electric charge $Q$ stored on a conductor to a difference in electric potential $V$ Units: Farads, $F = \frac{C}{V}$.</description></item><item><title>8: Memory Process</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mem-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mem-process/</guid><description>Three-Stage Model of Memory # Three-stage modal model of memory; Atkinson-Shiffrin model: Sensory memory Working memory or short-term memory Long-term memory Old model that&amp;rsquo;s not used today Sensory memory is seen as a type of perception Short term is similar to attention Interesting to study to see how our model evolved and how memories are processed Sensory memory # Holds sensory information very briefly (1/2 to 4 secs) If you stare at an image then close your eyes you can still see the image Large capacity store Sensory input is held very briefly in sensory memory to allow selection and processing of information Now often considered to be a part of perception (a) was flashed, then (b), and people reported seeing (c) [Eriksen &amp;amp; Collins, 1967]</description></item><item><title>9: Memory Strategies</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mem-strategies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mem-strategies/</guid><description>Memory strategies # Deep processing/meaning # Meaning/deep processing: processing information deeply (by its meaning) produces better recall at a later time than does shallow processing (attending to its appearance or sound) Mere repetition is not very effective in enhancing long-term memory, but understanding aids memory To enhance recall, use elaboration: relate new information to other information in memory Organization # Organization: effective organization of material greatly enhances recall Chunking: organizing items into familiar, manageable units Chunking lists of numbers, letters, or names can enhance memory E.</description></item><item><title>9: Op-Amps, Comparators &amp; Charge Sharing</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/9/</guid><description>\(\) 03/29: Operational Amplifier and Comparator # Dependent Sources # As briefly mentioned before, the voltage and current sources covered so far have been independent sources, meaning they have a constant, fixed value. However, dependent sources also generate currents and voltages but their output depends on some other &amp;ldquo;controlling&amp;rdquo; current .$i_x$ or voltage .$v_x$ in the circuit.
VCVS: Voltage-controlled voltage source .</description></item><item><title>10: Forgetting &amp; Reconstruction</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/forgetting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/forgetting/</guid><description>Are there limits to memory capacity? # Memory experts # Rajan Mahadevan memorized .$\pi$ to over 30,000 digit in 3 hours, 45 minutes; father had memorized all of Shakespeare’s sonnets Subconsciously done and primarily for numbers Russian journalist Shereshevskii &amp;ldquo;recalled everything he had ever seen or heard&amp;rdquo; Could report back 70 digits or words after only having heard them once Could recall list and circumstances under which he had learned it 15 years later Potentially first (recorded) case of Hyperthymesia Drawbacks of having a &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; memory Rajan: &amp;ldquo;As a child, I used to be so lost in my own thoughts, I would talk to myself.</description></item><item><title>10: NFB, DACs</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/eecs-16a/10/</guid><description>04/05: # Negative Feedback # Digital-to-Analog Converter # 04/07: #</description></item><item><title>10: Parametric Equations and Polar Coordinates</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/10/</guid><description>10.1 Curves Defined by Parametric Equations # Parametric equations are written as .$(f(t), g(t))$ They define curves (not functions!) Time .$t \in [t_i, t_f]$ Initial point: .$\big(f(t_i), g(t_i)\big)$ Terminal point: .$\big(f(t_f), g(t_f)\big)$ For parametric equation in form .$\big(h + r \cdot \sin(t), k + r \cdot \cos(t)\big)$ on .$t \in [0, 2\pi]$ , the resulting curve is a circle clockwise centered around the point .$(h,k)$ Likewise, .</description></item><item><title>11: Memory Topics</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mem-topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/mem-topics/</guid><description>Neurological Mind Reading # Team of neuroscientists at Carnegie Mellon led by Marcel Just are learning to read people’s minds based on fMRI cortical activation patterns
In early study, researchers were able to identify which of 10 similar objects (e.g., hammer vs. drill vs. screwdriver) people were viewing based on scans (Shinkareva, Mason, Malave et al., 2008) Lab has now also identified activation patterns associated with (Wang, Cherkassky, &amp;amp; Just, 2017) Different abstract ideas (e.</description></item><item><title>Anthro C12AC</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/anthro-c12ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/anthro-c12ac/</guid><description>Anthropocene # The time when human activity began to have an influence on (global) landscape due to our use of fire Large subject used in a range of fields &amp;ndash; no single definition Defining feature: combustion of carbon and greenhouse gases Ice core measurement technique As ice forms, methane and CO2 get trapped along with ash/dust/pollen which scientists can measure by coring Ice can be dated so we can compare these variables so we can see change in greenhouse gases over time Beginning is disputed Industrial revolution (1780s) Most popular among scholars Atomic Testing (1940s) The isotopic by-products of bomb testing provide a distinctive marker horizon in ice cores, ocean and lake sediments, and soils Stages idea: Includes vital events such as forest cutting and grassland conversion: the two largest spatial transformations of Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface in human history 1.</description></item><item><title>ASAMST 20A</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/asamst-20a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/asamst-20a/</guid><description>Week 1 (January 18 &amp;amp; 20): Introduction to the course. History, Memory, and Racialization # Reading: Tataki, Strangers from a Different Shore, Preface and Ch. 1: “From a Different Shore.”
What is Asian American Studies?
Panethnicity &amp;ldquo;pan&amp;rdquo; - a conglomeration &amp;ldquo;ethnicity&amp;rdquo; - belonging to a social group Panethnic identity example: Asian American Panethnicity Cultural Literacy One&amp;rsquo;s competency about their implicit biases Reading:</description></item><item><title>12: Imagery</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/imagery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/cogsci-c100/imagery/</guid><description>Controversies in Cognitive Science # How is information stored?
In analog code (i.e., as a pictorial representation) OR As a propositional code (i.e., descriptive representation)? Mental imagery # How Are Mental Representations Stored? # Experiments on mental imagery by Roger Shepard and Jacqueline Metzler in early 1970s spawned the imagery debate Suggested that some types of cognitive information processing involve forms of representation that are very different from how information is represented in, and manipulated by, a digital computer Imagery and rotation studies: Rotate each object on the left to see if it matches the object on the right: Amount of time it takes to rotate a mental image depends on the extent of the rotation One feature of digitally encoded information is that the length of time it takes to process a piece of information is typically a function only of the quantity of information (the number of bits that are required to encode it)</description></item><item><title>12: Vectors &amp; Geometry of Space</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/12/</guid><description>12.1 3D Coordinate Systems # Right hand rule: Index point to .$x$, thumb to .$z$, and write through .$y$ If you have point .$P(a,b,c)$ and drop a perpendicular dot on the .$xy$-plane at .$a,b,0$, you now have a projection of .$P$ onto the .$xy$-plane The distance .$|P_1 P_2|$ between two points .$P_1(x_1, y_1, z_1)$ and .$P_2(x_2, y_2, z_2)$ is $$|P_1 P_2| = \sqrt{(x_2-x_1)^2 + (y_2 - y_1)^2 + (z_2 - z_1)^2}$$ We can define the equation for a sphere with a center at .</description></item><item><title>13: Vector Functions</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/13/</guid><description>13.1 Vector Functions and Space Curves # Vector Functions # We can write a vector function as $$\vec r(t) = \langle f(t), g(t), h(t) \rangle = f(t) \hat i + g(t) \hat j + h(t) \hat k$$ The domain of .$\vec r$ consists of all values of .$t$ for which each of the terms are defined The limit of a vector function is $$\lim_{t\to a} \vec r(t) = \big\langle \lim_{t\to a} f(t), \lim_{t\to a} g(t), \lim_{t\to a} h(t) \big\rangle$$ .</description></item><item><title>14: Partial Derivatives</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/14/</guid><description>14.1 Functions of Several Variables # In the real world, most things don&amp;rsquo;t depend on a single variable Temperature may depend on the .$(x,y)$ (latitude/longitude) position Volume of a cylinder depends on radius .$r$ and height .$h$: .$V =\pi r^2 h$ Formal Definition: A function .$f$ of two variables is a rule that assigns to each ordered pair of real numbers .$(x,y)$ in a set .</description></item><item><title>15: Multiple Integrals</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/15/</guid><description>15.1 Double Integrals over Rectangles # We describe closed rectangles in the form .$R = [a,b] \times [c,b] = \{(x,y) \in \mathbb{R}^2 \vert a \leq x \leq b, c \leq y \leq d\}$ Then we can write the solid .$S$ that lies above .$R$ as .$S = \{(x,y,z) \in \mathbb{R}^3 \vert 0 \leq z \leq f(x,y), (x,y) \in R\}$ To find the volume of this surface, we take a double integral $$V = \iint_R f(x,y)\ dA$$ Fubini&amp;rsquo;s Theorem: If .</description></item><item><title>16: Vector Calculus</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/16/</guid><description>16.1 Vector Fields # A vector field in .$\mathbb{R}^3$ is a function .$\vec F$ on region .$E \in \mathbb{R}^3$ that assigns each point .$(x,y,z)$ a vector .$F(x,y,z)$ .$\vec F$ is made up of component function: .$\vec F(x,y,z) = \langle P(x,y,z)\hat i, Q(x,y,z) \hat j, R(x,y,z) \hat k\rangle$ .$\vec F$ is continuos iff its component vectors are continuos .$\vec F$ is conservative (path taken doesn&amp;rsquo;t change work) iff potential function .</description></item><item><title>17: Temperature, Thermal Expansion, &amp; Ideal Gas Law</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/17/</guid><description>17.1: Atomic Theory # Atoms are the smallest unit of matter Atomic unit: .$\text{u} = 1.66\cdot 10^{-27}$ kg E.x. Hydrogen weighs .$1.0078 \text{u}$ Molecular mass of a compound is the sum of the particles (atoms) in the compound Terms # Element: Substance that cannot be broken down into smaller substances (gold) Molecule: Group of atoms held together by covalent bonds Compound: Substance made from atoms combined in specific ratios Brownian Motion # Random movement seen in pollen/dust, as well as atoms Using Brownian motion, Einstein found the size of an atom to be .</description></item><item><title>18: Kinetic Theory of Gases</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/18/</guid><description>18.1 Ideal Gas Laws and Molecular Interpolation # Ideal Gas Law Assumptions # There are a large number of molecules, .$N$, each of mass .$m$ that move in random directions at random speeds Molecules are, on average, sufficiently far away from one another (separation .$\gg$ diameter) Molecules obey classical mechanics so .$KE \gg PE$ when colliding Collisions are perfectly elastic Micro and Macroscopic views related through Energy # In a system with .</description></item><item><title>19: Heat &amp; First Law of Thermo</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/19/</guid><description>\(\) 19.1 Heat as Energy Transfer # Units # Heat unit is calorie (cal) The amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of 1 gram of water by 1 celsius $$4.186 \text{ J} = 1 \text{ cal}$$ Kilocalorie (kcal, Calorie) is more common Amount of heat needed to raise 1 kg of water by 1 celsius $$4.186 \text{ kJ} = 1 \text{ kcal}$$ British system of units has British thermal units (Btu) One Btu is the heat needed to raise the temperature of 1 lb of water by 1 Fahrenheit $$1 \text{ Btu} = 0.</description></item><item><title>20: Second Law of Thermo</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/20/</guid><description>20.1 Intro # Second law states that systems only increase in entropy over time That is, most systems are on directional E.x. mixing salt and pepper together result in an mixture. No matter how much you keep mixing it, they won&amp;rsquo;t naturally separate and return to the initial state even though it follows first law of thermo (conserving energy) (Specific) Second Law of Thermo Heat can flow spontaneously from a hot object to a cold object; heat will not flow spontaneously from a cold object to a hot object.</description></item><item><title>21: Electric Charges &amp; Fields</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/21/</guid><description>21.1 Static Electricity; Electric Charge and its Conservation # &amp;ldquo;Charged&amp;rdquo; objects posses a net electric charge Unlike charges attract; like charges repel Charges on glass are positive, charges on plastic is negative Law of Conservation of Electric Charge: Whenever a certain amount of charge is produced in one object, an equal amount of the opposite type of charge is produced in another object Charges cannot be destroyed or created E.</description></item><item><title>22: Flux &amp; Gauss's Law</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/22/</guid><description>22.1 Electric Flux # Electric Flux: Electric field that passes through a given area E.x. for a uniform field .$\vec E$ passing through an area .$A$ at angle .$\theta$ between the field direction and line perpendicular to the area, the flux is defined as $$\Phi_\vec{E} = \vec E_\perp A = \vec EA_\perp = \vec E A \cos \theta = \vec E \cdot \vec A$$ The .</description></item><item><title>23: Electric Potential</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/23/</guid><description>23.1 Electric Potential Energy and Difference # PE can only be defined for conservative forces That is, work done by said force is independent of the path taken Coulomb&amp;rsquo;s Law is conservative because the dependence on position is conservative Hence, we define .$\Delta U = -W$ with .$\Delta U = U_b - U_a$ is for a situation where a point charge .$q$ moves from point .</description></item><item><title>24: Capacitance, Dielectrics, Electric Energy Storage</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/24/</guid><description>24.1 Capacitors # Capacitors are devices that store an electric charge Normally consists of two conducting objects; plates, sheets When a voltage is applied, the two plates become charged: one positive, one negative Conductors are placed near one another, but not touching This distance is typically due to an insulator between sheets Capacitors are typically rolled so that they take up less room Two main use cases Storing energy for later use; e.</description></item><item><title>25: Electric Current and Resistance</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/25/</guid><description>25.1 The Electric Battery # Batteries produce electricity by transforming chemical energy into electric energy Simple battery (cells) contain two plates or rods of dissimilar metals called electrodes The portion of rods outside of the solution are called the terminals Anode: The positive electrode Cathode: The negative electrode These electrodes are emersed in the electrolyte: a solution such as a dilute acid Chemical Process:</description></item><item><title>26: DC Circuits</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/26/</guid><description>26.1 EMF and Terminal Voltage # EMF # To have a current, we need an emf (electromotive force) device to transform one type of energy (chemical, mechanical, light) into electric energy The term “electromotive force” is a misnomer: it does not refer to a “force,” which is measured in newtons. To avoid confusion, we use the abbreviation, emf. EMF of the Source: The potential difference between the terminals of a source when no current flows to an external circuit .</description></item><item><title>27: Magnetism</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/27/</guid><description>27.1 Magnets and Magnetic Fields # Every magnet has two ends or faces called poles which are where the magnetic field is strongest If a magnet is suspended so it can move freely, one pole will point north Aptly, this side is called the north pole Magnetic poles aren&amp;rsquo;t like electric charge: Positive or negative charge can easily be isolated, but we can never isolate a magnetic pole That is, if you cut a magnet is half you don&amp;rsquo;t obtain isolated north and south poles.</description></item><item><title>28: Sources of Magnetic Field</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/28/</guid><description>28.1 Magnetic Field Due to a Straight Wire # Magnetic fields due to the electric current in a long straight wire forms circles with the wire at the center This field is proportional directly with current .$I$ and inversely with distance .$r$: $$B = \frac{\mu_0}{2\pi} \cdot \frac{I}{r}$$ .$\mu_0 = 4\pi \times 10^{-7} \text{ T$\cdot$m/A}$ is the permeability of free space 28.2 Force between Two Parallel Wires # Since current-carrying wires feel a force in magnetic fields, and because current-carrying wires emit magnetic fields, current-carrying wires exert a force on one another Magnetic field .</description></item><item><title>29: Electromagnetic Induction &amp; Faraday's Law</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/29/</guid><description>29–1 Induced EMF # A changing magnetic field induces an emf That is, changing .$\vec B$, not .$\vec B$ itself, induces current Constant magnetic fields produce no current in a conductor This process is called electromagnetic induction It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the magnet or coil moves, only that there is relative motion between the two (a) A current is induced when a magnet is moved toward a coil, momentarily increasing the magnetic field through the coil.</description></item><item><title>30: Inductance, Electromagnetic Oscillations, &amp; AC Circuits</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/30/</guid><description>30.1 Mutual Inductance # When two wires are near one another, they induce an emf in one another This emf is proportional to the rate of change of the flux passing through it The flux passing through the coil is generated by the other coil&amp;rsquo;s current If the two coils are held in place then the total flux is proportional to the mutual inductance $$M = \frac{N_2 \Phi_{21}}{I_1}$$ .</description></item><item><title>Trig Identities</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/trig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/trig/</guid><description>Reciprocal Identities # $$\sin(x)=\frac{1}{\csc(x)}$$ $$\cos(x)=\frac{1}{\sec(x)}$$ $$\tan(x)=\frac{\sin(x)}{\cos(x)}=\frac{1}{\cot(x)}$$ Pythagorean Identities # $$\sin^2(x) + \cos^2(x) = 1$$ $$1+\tan^2(x) = \sec^2(x)$$ $$1+\cot^2(x)=\csc^2(x)$$ Cofunction Identities # $$\sin\Big(\frac{\pi}{2}-x\Big) = \cos(x)$$ $$\csc\Big(\frac{\pi}{2}-x\Big) = \sec(x)$$ $$\cos\Big(\frac{\pi}{2}-x\Big) = \sin(x)$$ $$\sec\Big(\frac{\pi}{2}-x\Big) = \csc(x)$$ $$\tan\Big(\frac{\pi}{2}-x\Big) = \cot(x)$$ $$\cot\Big(\frac{\pi}{2}-x\Big) = \tan(x)$$ Even/Odd Identities # $$ \sin(-x) = -\sin(x)$$ $$ \csc(-x) = -\csc(x)$$ $$ \cos(-x) = \cos(x)$$ $$ \sec(-x) = \sec(x)$$ $$ \tan(-x) = - \tan(x)$$ $$ \cot(-x) = -\cot(x)$$ Bonus fact: .</description></item><item><title>Trig Calculus</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/trig-calc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/math-53/trig-calc/</guid><description>Derivatives # $$\frac{d}{dx} \tan(x) = 1 + \tan^2(x) = \sec^2(x)$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} \csc(x) = -\cot(x) \cdot \csc(x)$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} \sec(x) = \frac{\sin(x)}{\cos^2(x)} = \tan(x) \cdot \sec(x)$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} \cot(x) = -\csc^2(x)$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} \log_a(x) = \frac{1}{x\cdot \ln(a)}$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} a^u = a^x \cdot \ln (a) du$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} \sin^2(x) = \sin(2x)$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} \cos^2(x) = -\sin(2x)$$ $$\frac{d}{dx} \tan^2(x) = 2\tan(x)\cdot \sec^2(x)$$
Integrals # $$\int a^x dx = \bigg(\frac{1}{\ln(a)}\bigg) a^x + C $$ $$\int \tan(x) dx = -\ln\vert \cos(x) \vert + C$$ $$\int \tan^2(x) dx = \tan(x) - x + C$$ $$\int \csc(x) dx = \ln\vert \csc(x) - \cot(x)\vert + C = \ln \bigg\vert \tan\bigg(\frac{x}{2}\bigg)\bigg\vert + C$$ $$\int \csc^2(x) dx = -\cot(x) + C$$ $$\int \sec(x) dx = -\ln\vert \sec(x) + \tan(x)\vert + C$$ $$\int \sec^2(x) dx = \tan(x) + C$$ $$\int \cot(x) dx = \ln\vert \sin(x) \vert + C$$ $$\int \cot^2(x) dx = -\cot(x) - x + C$$ $$\int \frac{1}{\sin(ax)\cos(ax)} = \frac{1}{a} \ln\vert\tan(ax)\vert + C$$ $$\int \frac{1}{x\sqrt{x^2-a^2}} dx = \frac{1}{a} \sec^{-1}\bigg( \frac{\vert x \vert}{a}\bigg) + C$$ $$\int \frac{1}{\sqrt{a^2-x^2}} dx = \sin^{-1}\bigg( \frac{x}{a} \bigg) + C$$ $$\int \frac{1}{a^2 + x^2} dx = \frac{1}{a} \tan^{-1}\bigg( \frac{x}{a} \bigg) + C$$</description></item><item><title>AP Human Geography</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/ap/huge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/ap/huge/</guid><description>The content of these notes are solid, but formatting is not since they&amp;rsquo;re exported from Notion. 🗺️ Unit 1 — Thinking Geographically # Developing Understanding
This first unit sets the foundation for the course by teaching students how geographers approach the study of places. Students are encouraged to reflect on the “why of where” to better understand geographic perspectives. Many other high school courses ask students to read and analyze data, but for this course, students also apply a spatial perspective when reading and analyzing qualitative and quantitative data.</description></item><item><title>AP Physics C: Mechanics</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/ap/cmech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/ap/cmech/</guid><description>This are very disjoint notes I took long ago. I would recommend using this for practice qs and perhaps equation review after you have a solid understanding of the chapters. My other notes are much more comprehensive, I swear! :) 1. Kinematics # Four Primary Equations # $$\Delta x=\frac{1}{2}(v_f-v_i)\Delta t \text{ &amp;ndash; no } a$$ $$v_f=v_i+a\Delta t \text{ &amp;ndash; no } x$$ $$\Delta x=v_i \Delta t+\frac{1}{2}a \Delta t^2 \text{ &amp;ndash; no } v_f$$ $$\Delta x=v_f \Delta t-\frac{1}{2}a \Delta t^2 \text{ &amp;ndash; no } v_i$$ $$v_f^2=v_i^2+2a \Delta x \text{ &amp;ndash; no } t$$ Used when .</description></item><item><title>AP Statistics</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/ap/stats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/ap/stats/</guid><description>The content of these notes are solid, but formatting is not since they&amp;rsquo;re exported from Notion. Unit 1: Exploring One-Variable Data # Types of Variables # Categorical variables assigns labels that place each individual into a particular group, called a category. Zip code. hair color Quantitative variables takes number values that are quantities—counts or measurements. Height, GPA Explanatory x on graph independent variable — what we&amp;rsquo;re changing measures an outcome of a study.</description></item></channel></rss>