<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MCB C61 on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/mcb-c61/</link><description>Recent content in MCB C61 on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/mcb-c61/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1: Evolution of the Mind, the Brain, and Brain Chemistry</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/1/</guid><description>\(\) Origins # Key Idea; How long has the &amp;lsquo;human mind&amp;rsquo; been around?
Brief History # We have records of keeping track of astronomical events, e.x. Movement of the moon and sun across the sky Changes of the length of day Equinoxes, Solstices became ritual dates long ago (typically involved with religion) Phases of the moon (new/full moons) Stonehenge Rock structure in England 4,500 years old Speculated that this may have been an ancient astronomical observatory Cave paintings 15,000 &amp;ndash; 40,000 years old &amp;ndash; Paleolithic Discovered in December 1994 Chauvet, Lascoux, and others across SW Europe People went through an effort to go deep into caves with lamps to create these drawings &amp;ndash; thinking in sophisticated ways Ancient Music Have evidence of an ancient flute made from a bear bone 50,000 years ago Human evolution # Oldest fossils of a direct human ancestor are 5-6 MYA Volcanos spew radioactive elements which become buried Estimated that humans and chimps have evolved independently since 7 MYA Hominin fossils fall into 3 primary groups, or genera: Ardipithecus Climbs in woodlands Can walk on two legs Australopithecus Committed biped Small brain Big teeth and faces Homo Our genus &amp;ndash; homo sapiens &amp;ndash; are the only species remaining today Technological primate; depends on culture Found burial of dead (pets too) along with primitive instruments Species Age Brain Size cm$^3$ Ardipithecus ramidus ~ 4.</description></item><item><title>2: DNA, Synapses, and Neuroanatomy</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/2/</guid><description>\(\) 4: Genes and the History of Molecular Biology # Overview of History # Mid-1850s: Charles Darwin proposes that all life is deeply related and that there must be some underlying source of variation that is associated with how information is stored and passed on from one generation to the next. Gregor Mendel investigates inheritance in pea plants, which leads to the idea that information needed to build an organism is packaged into a gene &amp;ndash; some abstract kind of units associated with specific traits, segregated and sorted in reproduction 1920s: Based on groundwork laid by Max Planck in 1900 and Albert Einstein in 1905, a large group of physicists begin to develop Quantum Mechanics.</description></item><item><title>3: Pharmacology; Neurodevelopment</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/3/</guid><description>\(\) 8: Poison, Medicine, and Pharmacology # Pharmakon: medicine and poison at the same time Everything is a poison. The difference between a poison and a remedy depends on the dose. &amp;ndash; Paracelsus
Botulinum Toxin Strongest toxin known Disrupts acetylcholine transmitters of neuromuscular junctions Human LD$_{50}$ = lethal dose for 50%: 2 ng / kg E.x. lethal dose for 50kg is 100ng Therapeutic (Botox) dosage: ~5ng Therapeutic Index (TI): lethal dose / therapeutic dose E.</description></item><item><title>4: Sensory Perception</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/4/</guid><description>\(\) 11: Sensory Perception # Sensation # Detection and capacity to respond to some signal; Property of all living organism
Microorganisms can detect and respond to physical stimuli Chemotaxis (reaction to chemicals, i.e sugar) has been observed in ecoli through movement by &amp;lsquo;swimming&amp;rsquo; with runs and tumbles Phototaxis: Moving toward light (e.x. bacteria) Phototropism: Bending towards light (e.x. plant) Perception # The experience of said a signal; constructive process occurring with our nervous system</description></item><item><title>5: Connectivity</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/mcb-c61/5/</guid><description>\(\) 16: Skin, Touch, and Movement # Somatosensory receptors occur in the skin Dorsal-root ganglion (DRG) is a somatosensory neuron that carries &amp;rsquo;touch&amp;rsquo; information Somatosensory cortex is where information is processed Located in postcentral gyrus Somatosensory body map pairs region in cortex and location on body Discovered by Wilder Penfield Size in cortex isn&amp;rsquo;t 1:1 with size (index finger has an extra-large area) &amp;ldquo;Distortion&amp;rdquo; reflects sensory sensitivity E.x. difficult to sense two points of contact (on back); Two-point discrimination test Finger amputation in monkey increased cortical response for adjacent fingers (somatosensory map reorganization) Phantom limb&amp;rsquo;s may occur when one loose&amp;rsquo;s their arm and &amp;lsquo;feels&amp;rsquo; said arm when receives information from cortical-adjacent areas Primary somatosensory cortex (S1) lesions lead to loss of sensation in specific region Posterior somatosensory cortex (S2, S3, etc) lesions lead to neglect syndrome: one is aware, but unable to focus on a body region (ex.</description></item></channel></rss>