<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Physics 7B on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/physics-7b/</link><description>Recent content in Physics 7B on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/physics-7b/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>17: Temperature, Thermal Expansion, &amp; Ideal Gas Law</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/17/</guid><description>17.1: Atomic Theory # Atoms are the smallest unit of matter Atomic unit: .$\text{u} = 1.66\cdot 10^{-27}$ kg E.x. Hydrogen weighs .$1.0078 \text{u}$ Molecular mass of a compound is the sum of the particles (atoms) in the compound Terms # Element: Substance that cannot be broken down into smaller substances (gold) Molecule: Group of atoms held together by covalent bonds Compound: Substance made from atoms combined in specific ratios Brownian Motion # Random movement seen in pollen/dust, as well as atoms Using Brownian motion, Einstein found the size of an atom to be .</description></item><item><title>18: Kinetic Theory of Gases</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/18/</guid><description>18.1 Ideal Gas Laws and Molecular Interpolation # Ideal Gas Law Assumptions # There are a large number of molecules, .$N$, each of mass .$m$ that move in random directions at random speeds Molecules are, on average, sufficiently far away from one another (separation .$\gg$ diameter) Molecules obey classical mechanics so .$KE \gg PE$ when colliding Collisions are perfectly elastic Micro and Macroscopic views related through Energy # In a system with .</description></item><item><title>19: Heat &amp; First Law of Thermo</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/19/</guid><description>19.1 Heat as Energy Transfer # Units # Heat unit is calorie (cal) The amount of heat needed to raise the temperature of 1 gram of water by 1 celsius $$4.186 \text{ J} = 1 \text{ cal}$$ Kilocalorie (kcal, Calorie) is more common Amount of heat needed to raise 1 kg of water by 1 celsius $$4.186 \text{ kJ} = 1 \text{ kcal}$$ British system of units has British thermal units (Btu) One Btu is the heat needed to raise the temperature of 1 lb of water by 1 Fahrenheit $$1 \text{ Btu} = 0.</description></item><item><title>20: Second Law of Thermo</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/20/</guid><description>20.1 Intro # Second law states that systems only increase in entropy over time That is, most systems are on directional E.x. mixing salt and pepper together result in an mixture. No matter how much you keep mixing it, they won&amp;rsquo;t naturally separate and return to the initial state even though it follows first law of thermo (conserving energy) (Specific) Second Law of Thermo Heat can flow spontaneously from a hot object to a cold object; heat will not flow spontaneously from a cold object to a hot object.</description></item><item><title>21: Electric Charges &amp; Fields</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/21/</guid><description>21.1 Static Electricity; Electric Charge and its Conservation # &amp;ldquo;Charged&amp;rdquo; objects posses a net electric charge Unlike charges attract; like charges repel Charges on glass are positive, charges on plastic is negative Law of Conservation of Electric Charge: Whenever a certain amount of charge is produced in one object, an equal amount of the opposite type of charge is produced in another object Charges cannot be destroyed or created E.</description></item><item><title>22: Flux &amp; Gauss's Law</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/22/</guid><description>22.1 Electric Flux # Electric Flux: Electric field that passes through a given area E.x. for a uniform field .$\vec E$ passing through an area .$A$ at angle .$\theta$ between the field direction and line perpendicular to the area, the flux is defined as $$\Phi_\vec{E} = \vec E_\perp A = \vec EA_\perp = \vec E A \cos \theta = \vec E \cdot \vec A$$ The number of field lines passing through unit area perpendicular to the field .</description></item><item><title>23: Electric Potential</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/23/</guid><description>23.1 Electric Potential Energy and Difference # PE can only be defined for conservative forces That is, work done by said force is independent of the path taken Coulomb’s Law is conservative because the dependence on position is conservative Hence, we define .$\Delta U = -W$ with .$\Delta U = U_b - U_a$ is for a situation where a point charge .$q$ moves from point .</description></item><item><title>24: Capacitance, Dielectrics, Electric Energy Storage</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/24/</guid><description>24.1 Capacitors # Capacitors are devices that store an electric charge Normally consists of two conducting objects; plates, sheets When a voltage is applied, the two plates become charged: one positive, one negative Conductors are placed near one another, but not touching This distance is typically due to an insulator between sheets Capacitors are typically rolled so that they take up less room Two main use cases Storing energy for later use; e.</description></item><item><title>25: Electric Current and Resistance</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/25/</guid><description>25.1 The Electric Battery # Batteries produce electricity by transforming chemical energy into electric energy Simple battery (cells) contain two plates or rods of dissimilar metals called electrodes The portion of rods outside of the solution are called the terminals Anode: The positive electrode Cathode: The negative electrode These electrodes are emersed in the electrolyte: a solution such as a dilute acid Chemical Process:</description></item><item><title>26: DC Circuits</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/26/</guid><description>26.1 EMF and Terminal Voltage # EMF To have a current, we need an emf (electromotive force) device to transform one type of energy (chemical, mechanical, light) into electric energy The term “electromotive force” is a misnomer: it does not refer to a “force,” which is measured in newtons. To avoid confusion, we use the abbreviation, emf. EMF of the Source: The potential difference between the terminals of a source when no current flows to an external circuit .</description></item><item><title>27: Magnetism</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/27/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/27/</guid><description>27.1 Magnets and Magnetic Fields # Every magnet has two ends or faces called poles which are where the magnetic field is strongest If a magnet is suspended so it can move freely, one pole will point north Aptly, this side is called the north pole Magnetic poles aren&amp;rsquo;t like electric charge: Positive or negative charge can easily be isolated, but we can never isolate a magnetic pole That is, if you cut a magnet is half you don&amp;rsquo;t obtain isolated north and south poles.</description></item><item><title>28: Sources of Magnetic Field</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/28/</guid><description>28.1 Magnetic Field Due to a Straight Wire # Magnetic fields due to the electric current in a long straight wire forms circles with the wire at the center This field is proportional directly with current .$I$ and inversely with distance .$r$: $$B = \frac{\mu_0}{2\pi} \cdot \frac{I}{r}$$ .$\mu_0 = 4\pi \times 10^{-7} \text{ T$\cdot$m/A}$ is the permeability of free space 28.2 Force between Two Parallel Wires # Since current-carrying wires feel a force in magnetic fields, and because current-carrying wires emit magnetic fields, current-carrying wires exert a force on one another Magnetic field .</description></item><item><title>29: Electromagnetic Induction &amp; Faraday's Law</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/29/</guid><description>29–1 Induced EMF # A changing magnetic field induces an emf That is, changing .$\vec B$, not .$\vec B$ itself, induces current Constant magnetic fields produce no current in a conductor This process is called electromagnetic induction It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the magnet or coil moves, only that there is relative motion between the two (a) A current is induced when a magnet is moved toward a coil, momentarily increasing the magnetic field through the coil.</description></item><item><title>30: Inductance, Electromagnetic Oscillations, &amp; AC Circuits</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/physics-7b/30/</guid><description>30.1 Mutual Inductance # When two wires are near one another, they induce an emf in one another This emf is proportional to the rate of change of the flux passing through it The flux passing through the coil is generated by the other coil&amp;rsquo;s current If the two coils are held in place then the total flux is proportional to the mutual inductance $$M = \frac{N_2 \Phi_{21}}{I_1}$$ .</description></item></channel></rss>