<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anthro C12AC</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/anthro-c12ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/anthro-c12ac/</guid><description>Anthropocene # The time when human activity began to have an influence on (global) landscape due to our use of fire Large subject used in a range of fields &amp;ndash; no single definition Defining feature: combustion of carbon and greenhouse gases Ice core measurement technique As ice forms, methane and CO2 get trapped along with ash/dust/pollen which scientists can measure by coring Ice can be dated so we can compare these variables so we can see change in greenhouse gases over time Beginning is disputed Industrial revolution (1780s) Most popular among scholars Atomic Testing (1940s) The isotopic by-products of bomb testing provide a distinctive marker horizon in ice cores, ocean and lake sediments, and soils Stages idea: Includes vital events such as forest cutting and grassland conversion: the two largest spatial transformations of Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface in human history 1.</description></item><item><title>ASAMST 20A</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/asamst-20a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/asamst-20a/</guid><description>Week 1 (January 18 &amp;amp; 20): Introduction to the course. History, Memory, and Racialization # Reading: Tataki, Strangers from a Different Shore, Preface and Ch. 1: “From a Different Shore.”
What is Asian American Studies?
Panethnicity &amp;ldquo;pan&amp;rdquo; - a conglomeration &amp;ldquo;ethnicity&amp;rdquo; - belonging to a social group Panethnic identity example: Asian American Panethnicity Cultural Literacy One&amp;rsquo;s competency about their implicit biases Reading:
Angel Island versus Ellis Island Angel Island was the west coast immigration entry point for people coming from the west (mainly Asian migration) Ellis Island was the entry point for many immigrrants from the east (mainly European) &amp;ldquo;Multiculuralism was a find of fear and optimism around how we are a very mixed country and what binds us together is this appreciation of different ethnic backgrounds, but we also assimilate under some cultural practice/viewpoint&amp;rdquo; - Michael Chang</description></item></channel></rss>