<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engineering 29 on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/e-29/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering 29 on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/e-29/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 0: Intro &amp; Tolerancing</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/0/</guid><description>01-18: Course introduction # Overview # This class focuses on three main components &amp;ndash; manufacturing processes, dimensional tolerances, and design communication &amp;ndash; and how they interact with one another.
The class is made up of 9 modules:
Fundamentals Subtractive manufacturing processes Additive manufacturing processes Forming processes Joining processes Graphical visualization techniques Metrology: measuring manufactured objects Geometric dimensioning and tolerancing The future of manufacturing Why manufacturing? # In 2018, U.</description></item><item><title>Week 1: Fundamentals of Graphical Communication &amp; Subtractive Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/1/</guid><description>01-25: Fundamentals of graphical communication # These are notes are also on notes.mehvix.com/e-29/1/
Evolution of graphical visualization # Hand drawing Instrument drawing (using mechanical things to measure distances) 2D CAD (initially only able to draw side views) 3D CAD (solid modeling) Automatic generation of 2D working drawings Enable easy communication of measurements between designer and manufacturer Created with the assumption that manufactured objects are made up of elementary objects, geons?</description></item><item><title>Week 2: Cutting-based Processes &amp; Other Subtractive Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/2/</guid><description>02-01 Cutting-based Processes # Modeling of material cutting # Chips are created and separated from the work by plastic deformation, i.e. shearing, of the work. Sheer plane is created by the tool (teal segment) Throughout the shear plane, the shear stress must equal or exceed the shear strength of the work material for cutting to proceed. The value of the shear angle is not something that we directly control, but depends on several factors.</description></item></channel></rss>