<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Engineering 29 on notes.mehvix.com</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/e-29/</link><description>Recent content in Engineering 29 on notes.mehvix.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://notes.mehvix.com/docs/e-29/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 0: Intro &amp; Tolerancing</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/0/</guid><description>01-18: Course introduction # Overview # This class focuses on three main components &amp;ndash; manufacturing processes, dimensional tolerances, and design communication &amp;ndash; and how they interact with one another.
The class is made up of 9 modules:
Fundamentals Subtractive manufacturing processes Additive manufacturing processes Forming processes Joining processes Graphical visualization techniques Metrology: measuring manufactured objects Geometric dimensioning and tolerancing The future of manufacturing Why manufacturing? # In 2018, U.</description></item><item><title>Week 1: Fundamentals of Graphical Communication &amp; Subtractive Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/1/</guid><description>01-25: Fundamentals of graphical communication # Evolution of graphical visualization # Hand drawing Instrument drawing (using mechanical things to measure distances) 2D CAD (initially only able to draw side views) 3D CAD (solid modeling) Automatic generation of 2D working drawings Enable easy communication of measurements between designer and manufacturer Created with the assumption that manufactured objects are made up of elementary objects, geons? Now we have the ability to run algos to analyze models, removing unnecessary bits We&amp;rsquo;re moving towards computer-generated geometry that&amp;rsquo;s contained by human input # Increasingly complex geometries Topological optimization Internal lattices The way we interface with drawings has to keep up with this New interfaces Virtual and augmented reality for visualizing designs Why bother sketching by hand?</description></item><item><title>Week 2: Cutting-based Processes &amp; Other Subtractive Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/2/</guid><description>02-01 Cutting-based Processes # Modeling of material cutting # Chips are created and separated from the work by plastic deformation, i.e. shearing, of the work. Sheer plane is created by the tool (teal segment) Throughout the shear plane, the shear stress must equal or exceed the shear strength of the work material for cutting to proceed. The value of the shear angle is not something that we directly control, but depends on several factors.</description></item><item><title>Week 3: Additive Processes: Intro &amp; Extrusion</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/3/</guid><description>The rise of additive manufacturing # Additive manufacturing or “3D printing” has been receiving enormous attention both in industry and as a tool for education and design. Something that sets additive manufacturing apart from other families of processes is the enormous rate of innovation in process technology and machine design, together with the fact that much of this innovation is done by small start-up companies and even by individuals, with the development in some cases being crowd-funded.</description></item><item><title>Week 4: Additive Processes: Light-based, etc.</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/4/</guid><description>Processes based on light-sensitive liquids # Stereolithography (SLA) # Also called Digital Light Printing (DLP) Thermoforming molds are most commonly made with stereolithography, i.e orthodontic aligners Used because the molds need complete geometric customizability A tray, bath or vat of a photo-sensitive liquid (a resin) is locally crosslinked (solidified) with a scanning laser beam or projected light pattern (i.e Photoinitiator), usually violet (~405 nm) or ultraviolet (~365 nm) Unwanted bonding can be avoided by making the base oxygen-permeable (e.</description></item><item><title>Weeks 5 &amp; 6: Forming Processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/5/</guid><description>Before # So far in the class, we have seen a wide range of additive and subtractive processes which are capable of creating components in metals, alloys, polymeric materials, ceramics, and composites. The one thing that these processes all have in common is that they are serial — meaning that one feature is produced after another in a predefined sequence. This serial nature inherently limits productivity and may require considerable operator skill.</description></item><item><title>Weeks 6 &amp; 7: Joining processes</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/6/</guid><description>\(\) Joining Processes # Welding-based # There are many ways of assembling mechanical components to create mechanisms and structures. Examples of joining processes include the use of fasteners such as bolts and rivets, adhesives, and push fits, in which interference is used to connect components together. Welding, meanwhile, involves fusing two components by melting the material near their interface, and possibly introducing additional material of the same kind to fill any gaps between the components.</description></item><item><title>Week 7-8: Visualization</title><link>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://notes.mehvix.com/e-29/7/</guid><description>Orthographic projections # Formal (working) drawings: purpose # Need a formal way of documenting designs Legal documents i.e patents; contracts may rely on them Must stand on their own &amp;ndash; readable to any human No subsequent explanation No verbal assists No ambiguity Solution: multi-view orthographic projection World-wide engineering standard Can easily include tolerances What is a projection?</description></item></channel></rss>